<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerPlatform on Keith Atherton</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/powerplatform/</link><description>Recent content in PowerPlatform on Keith Atherton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/powerplatform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Licensing Ready Website</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-26-get-licensing-ready-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-26-get-licensing-ready-website/</guid><description>Get Licensing Ready website Microsoft products such as Azure and Power Platform have a variety of licencing options.
The Get Licensing Ready website provides material to learn about these licences and to take exams to earn certifications for free! 🎉
Courses available The website contains the following categories:
Getting started Microsoft products Microsoft programs New tracks Prior GLR tracks Each category contains one or more courses. For example, the Microsoft products category contains the following courses:</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Build 2023 - Microsoft Learn Cloud Skills Challenge</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-12-msbuild2023-cloud-skills-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-12-msbuild2023-cloud-skills-challenge/</guid><description>The Microsoft Build 2023 - Microsoft Learn Cloud Skills Challenge is now available! 🎉
Take one of the following 8 challenges to earn a free Microsoft Certification exam:
AI-900: Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals
Aligning Challenge: Microsoft Build: Azure AI Challenge AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator
Aligning Challenge: Not applicable / take any challenge AZ-204: Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure
Aligning Challenge: Not applicable / take any challenge AZ-305: Designing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions</description></item><item><title>Dynamics 365 and Microsoft Power Platform Release Planner</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-31-d365-pp-release-planner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-31-d365-pp-release-planner/</guid><description>I recently started paying more attention to the Dynamics 365 and Microsoft Power Platform Release Planner to learn about planned features, features coming soon, and features available to try now.
The release planner does cover Dynamics 365 and Microsoft Power Platform but my main focus is on Microsoft Power Platform.
Selecting a feature provides more information such as the description of the feature, who the feature is aimed at (admins, makers, etc), when the release is scheduled for phases like Public Preview and General Availability (GA), and much more:</description></item><item><title>Power Apps Super User</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-24-power-apps-super-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-24-power-apps-super-user/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve been awarded Power Apps Super User in 2023 Season 1 by the awesome Microsoft Power Platform Community!
Helping others is a privilege and something I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about. I&amp;rsquo;m also very grateful to everyone who has helped and supported me.
Here is the official announcement: https://powerusers.microsoft.com/t5/News-Announcements/Announcing-Super-Users-2023-Season-1/td-p/2066953
Check out the Microsoft Power Platform Community here: https://powerusers.microsoft.com/</description></item><item><title>Asking ChatGPT about the Microsoft Power Platform</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-10-asking-chatgpt-about-power-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-10-asking-chatgpt-about-power-platform/</guid><description>I wondered what ChatGPT thinks about the Microsoft Power Platform&amp;hellip; so I asked it! The results were very interesting - here they are:
Me: What is the Microsoft Power Platform?
ChatGPT: The Microsoft Power Platform is a low-code platform that enables organizations to build custom business applications quickly and easily. It combines three products: Power Apps, Power Automate (formerly known as Microsoft Flow), and Power BI.
Power Apps is a platform for creating custom business applications for mobile devices and web browsers.</description></item><item><title>Power Platform 2023 Release Wave 1 Plan</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</guid><description>The Microsoft Power Platform 2023 release wave 1 plan was recently announced with a TON of interesting updates!
The release plan contains hundreds of new features across Power Platform so here is a brief summary of some of my highlights:
Power BI Integrate Power BI into Teams meetings Power BI is adding new in-meeting experiences for Microsoft Teams. Users can add content like reports to Teams meetings by adding the Power BI tab to their meetings.</description></item></channel></rss>