<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerApps on Keith Atherton</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/powerapps/</link><description>Recent content in PowerApps on Keith Atherton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/powerapps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Power Apps Super User</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-24-power-apps-super-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-24-power-apps-super-user/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve been awarded Power Apps Super User in 2023 Season 1 by the awesome Microsoft Power Platform Community!
Helping others is a privilege and something I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about. I&amp;rsquo;m also very grateful to everyone who has helped and supported me.
Here is the official announcement: https://powerusers.microsoft.com/t5/News-Announcements/Announcing-Super-Users-2023-Season-1/td-p/2066953
Check out the Microsoft Power Platform Community here: https://powerusers.microsoft.com/</description></item><item><title>What is the Microsoft Power Apps Community?</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-03-what-is-power-apps-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-03-what-is-power-apps-community/</guid><description>The Microsoft Power Apps Community is a place where you can connect with peers, share ideas, and learn from experts for everything Power App-related.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great place to find help as well as offer help to others. In fact, when searching on Google (other search engines are available) for answers to Power App questions, I&amp;rsquo;m often directed to the Microsoft Power Apps Community where, often, someone has encountered a similar issue and helpful folks have responded with a solution.</description></item><item><title>Power Platform 2023 Release Wave 1 Plan</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</guid><description>The Microsoft Power Platform 2023 release wave 1 plan was recently announced with a TON of interesting updates!
The release plan contains hundreds of new features across Power Platform so here is a brief summary of some of my highlights:
Power BI Integrate Power BI into Teams meetings Power BI is adding new in-meeting experiences for Microsoft Teams. Users can add content like reports to Teams meetings by adding the Power BI tab to their meetings.</description></item><item><title>Power Apps Ideas</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-28-power-apps-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-28-power-apps-ideas/</guid><description>Picture this: You have a Power App gallery which contains employee name text data using Power Fx formula ThisItem.Name:
Next, you want to change the text format from &amp;ldquo;Peter Gibbons&amp;rdquo; to, say, &amp;ldquo;Gibbons, Peter&amp;rdquo;.
However, you&amp;rsquo;re not (yet) a Power Fx guru. What can you do???
Well, a feature which I&amp;rsquo;ve found useful is Power Apps Ideas which allows you to transform examples to Power Fx formulas by using the power of AI models.</description></item></channel></rss>