<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Certifications on Keith Atherton</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/certifications/</link><description>Recent content in Certifications on Keith Atherton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/certifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microsoft Power Platform Certifications</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-07-21-power-platform-certifications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-07-21-power-platform-certifications/</guid><description>Want to learn about Microsoft Power Platform Certifications but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start? Here are some tips!
Note: All information and screenshots are correct at time of writing but may be different in future as Microsoft certifications are subject to change (and often do!).
Which Power Platform-related certifications are available? Power Platform-related certification can be found here on Microsoft Learn:
https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/certifications/browse/?products=power-platform&amp;amp;resource_type=certification&amp;amp;expanded=power-platform
You&amp;rsquo;ll see several certifications with exams prefixed with PL- which cover various Power Platform services such as Power Apps, Power Automate, and Power BI.</description></item><item><title>Azure Data Fundamentals DP-900 Courses on LinkedIn Learning</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-13-dp-900-courses-on-lil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-13-dp-900-courses-on-lil/</guid><description>One of my favourite Microsoft certifications is Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals which requires passing Exam DP-900: Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals.
LinkedIn Learning now has courses for all four of the skills measured, and I was lucky enough to be one of the instructors:
Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900) Cert Prep: 1 Core Data Concepts by Gregor Suttie
Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900) Cert Prep: 2 Working with Relational Data on Azure by Adam Wilbert</description></item></channel></rss>