<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MicrosoftCertification on Keith Atherton</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/microsoftcertification/</link><description>Recent content in MicrosoftCertification on Keith Atherton</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.keithatherton.com/tags/microsoftcertification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microsoft Build 2023 - Microsoft Learn Cloud Skills Challenge</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-12-msbuild2023-cloud-skills-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-12-msbuild2023-cloud-skills-challenge/</guid><description>The Microsoft Build 2023 - Microsoft Learn Cloud Skills Challenge is now available! 🎉
Take one of the following 8 challenges to earn a free Microsoft Certification exam:
AI-900: Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals
Aligning Challenge: Microsoft Build: Azure AI Challenge AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator
Aligning Challenge: Not applicable / take any challenge AZ-204: Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure
Aligning Challenge: Not applicable / take any challenge AZ-305: Designing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions</description></item><item><title>How to Prepare for Microsoft Azure Certifications</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-13-prep-for-azure-certs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-13-prep-for-azure-certs/</guid><description>Azure Spring Clean 2023 This special blog post is part of the amazing Azure Spring Clean 2023 event organised by the awesome Joe Carlyle and Thomas Thornton.
Microsoft Azure certifications have many benefits, including the potential to get your first job working with Azure, earn a promotion, keeping your skills up to date, and having greater job satisfaction.
In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover which certifications are available, learning resources, exams and renewals, money-saving tips and much more!</description></item><item><title>My Microsoft Certification Journey</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-17-my-microsoft-certification-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-17-my-microsoft-certification-journey/</guid><description>My Microsoft certifications I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to have earned all eight Microsoft Fundamentals Certifications:
Azure Fundamentals Azure Data Fundamentals Azure AI Fundamentals Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals Power Platform Fundamentals Microsoft 365 Certified: Fundamentals Dynamics 365 Fundamentals (CRM) Dynamics 365 Fundamentals (ERP) Why I study for Microsoft certifications Studying for a technical certification, Microsoft or otherwise, is a personal choice which can be motivated by several factors such as:</description></item></channel></rss>