<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Keith Atherton</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Keith Atherton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Architecture Modernization Book Review</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-11-22-architecture-modernization-book-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-11-22-architecture-modernization-book-review/</guid><description>The book This is my review of the book Architecture Modernization: Socio-technical alignment of software, strategy, and structure by Nick Tune with Jean-Georges Perrin.
The official book desciption is as follows:
Concrete tools, techniques, and processes to align software architecture with your business domains, organizational design, team topologies, and corporate strategy.
I selected this book as I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to improve my solution architecture skills, and this book&amp;rsquo;s description sounded like a holistic approach to software design covering the software, strategy, and structure of architecture.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Power Platform Certifications</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-07-21-power-platform-certifications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-07-21-power-platform-certifications/</guid><description>Want to learn about Microsoft Power Platform Certifications but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start? Here are some tips!
Note: All information and screenshots are correct at time of writing but may be different in future as Microsoft certifications are subject to change (and often do!)
Which Power Platform-related certifications are available? Power Platform-related certification can be found here on Microsoft Learn:
https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/certifications/browse/?products=power-platform&amp;amp;resource_type=certification&amp;amp;expanded=power-platform
You&amp;rsquo;ll see several certifications with exams prefixed with PL- which cover various Power Platform services such as Power Apps, Power Automate, and Power BI.</description></item><item><title>My Microsoft MVP Award</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-06-09-mvp-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-06-09-mvp-award/</guid><description>My Microsoft MVP Award I&amp;rsquo;m honoured to have received the Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) award for Business Applications in recognition of my &amp;ldquo;exceptional technical community leadership&amp;rdquo;!
Microsoft state:
MVPs are technology experts who passionately share their knowledge with the community.
Huge thank you to everyone who has supported me and helped with opportunities along the way - and that includes YOU for being an awesome supporter who reads my blog!</description></item><item><title>#100DaysOfSelfCare</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-06-02-100daysofselfcare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-06-02-100daysofselfcare/</guid><description>What is #100DaysOfSelfCare? During Mental Health Awareness Week in May 2023, the wonderful Azure McFarlane and I started a movement on Twitter with the hashtag #100DaysOfSelfCare.
Here is the first tweet: https://twitter.com/MrKeithAtherton/status/1658537794732523521
What is self-care? Self-care is anything you do to take care of yourself so you can stay physically, mentally, and emotionally well.
It can be as simple as going for a gentle walk or having lunch away from your desk, to learning something new or trying a new experience.</description></item><item><title>Get Licensing Ready Website</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-26-get-licensing-ready-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-26-get-licensing-ready-website/</guid><description>Get Licensing Ready website Microsoft products such as Azure and Power Platform have a variety of licencing options.
The Get Licensing Ready website provides material to learn about these licences and to take exams to earn certifications for free! 🎉
Courses available The website contains the following categories:
Getting started Microsoft products Microsoft programs New tracks Prior GLR tracks Each category contains one or more courses. For example, the Microsoft products category contains the following courses:</description></item><item><title>Power Apps Host Object</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-17-power-apps-host-object/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-17-power-apps-host-object/</guid><description>The Power Apps Host object The new Host object in Power Apps provides information about the current host running the app.
The Host object does not have any properties that accept formulas but you can call functions against it to retrieve the following information:
BrowserUserAgent: The complete user agent string that the browser uses to identify itself when running the app
OSType: The name of the operating system where the app is running</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Build 2023 - Microsoft Learn Cloud Skills Challenge</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-12-msbuild2023-cloud-skills-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-12-msbuild2023-cloud-skills-challenge/</guid><description>The Microsoft Build 2023 - Microsoft Learn Cloud Skills Challenge is now available! 🎉
Take one of the following 8 challenges to earn a free Microsoft Certification exam:
AI-900: Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals
Aligning Challenge: Microsoft Build: Azure AI Challenge AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator
Aligning Challenge: Not applicable / take any challenge AZ-204: Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure
Aligning Challenge: Not applicable / take any challenge AZ-305: Designing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions</description></item><item><title>Power App Gallery Control / ForAll Gotcha</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-05-power-app-gallery-forall-gotcha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-05-05-power-app-gallery-forall-gotcha/</guid><description>Recently, I came across a Power App gallery control / ForAll gotcha which I managed to handle so I&amp;rsquo;m sharing this here in case anyone else experiences the same issue.
OK, let&amp;rsquo;s set the scene: It&amp;rsquo;s a sunny Thursday afternoon in May in central Scotland. The hero is working on a Power App, and binds the following collection (colItems) to a gallery control:
ClearCollect(colItems, { ID:1, Name:&amp;#34;Dog&amp;#34; }, { ID:2, Name:&amp;#34;Cat&amp;#34; }, { ID:3, Name:&amp;#34;Rabbit&amp;#34; } ); Great, the gallery is showing the data collection as expected!</description></item><item><title>Power App Mobile QR Code</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-04-28-power-app-mobile-qr-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-04-28-power-app-mobile-qr-code/</guid><description>Super quick way to open a Power App on your mobile device: scan the Power App&amp;rsquo;s mobile QR code in the app&amp;rsquo;s Details section!
More info: https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/power-apps/mobile/scan-qr-code</description></item><item><title>Power Apps Ideas Website</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-04-14-power-apps-ideas-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-04-14-power-apps-ideas-website/</guid><description>If you have an idea for Power Apps - for example, a new feature - then you can post it to Power Apps Ideas website:
https://ideas.powerapps.com/
When submitting a new idea, you complete the following form. It&amp;rsquo;s worth adding plenty of detail:
Submissions on the site can then be up-voted by the community to highlight which ideas have the most demand, and you can also add comments.
Ideas can be assigned status values such as Under Review, Planned, Completed, and Declined.</description></item><item><title>Copilot in Microsoft Power Apps</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-04-07-power-apps-copilot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-04-07-power-apps-copilot/</guid><description>Copilot in Microsoft Power Apps OK, I hope you&amp;rsquo;re sitting down. An announcement was made recently which blew my mind: Copilot in Microsoft Power Apps (preview)!
This feature is made possible by use of next-generation AI technology and means you can write a sentence such as:
Build an app to manage music playlists for my favourite artists such as Metallica
(Well, that&amp;rsquo;s one example but the choice is yours 😄)</description></item><item><title>Dynamics 365 and Microsoft Power Platform Release Planner</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-31-d365-pp-release-planner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-31-d365-pp-release-planner/</guid><description>I recently started paying more attention to the Dynamics 365 and Microsoft Power Platform Release Planner to learn about planned features, features coming soon, and features available to try now.
The release planner does cover Dynamics 365 and Microsoft Power Platform but my main focus is on Microsoft Power Platform.
Selecting a feature provides more information such as the description of the feature, who the feature is aimed at (admins, makers, etc), when the release is scheduled for phases like Public Preview and General Availability (GA), and much more:</description></item><item><title>Power Apps Super User</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-24-power-apps-super-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-24-power-apps-super-user/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve been awarded Power Apps Super User in 2023 Season 1 by the awesome Microsoft Power Platform Community!
Helping others is a privilege and something I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about. I&amp;rsquo;m also very grateful to everyone who has helped and supported me.
Here is the official announcement: https://powerusers.microsoft.com/t5/News-Announcements/Announcing-Super-Users-2023-Season-1/td-p/2066953
Check out the Microsoft Power Platform Community here: https://powerusers.microsoft.com/</description></item><item><title>How to Prepare for Microsoft Azure Certifications</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-13-prep-for-azure-certs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-03-13-prep-for-azure-certs/</guid><description>Azure Spring Clean 2023 This special blog post is part of the amazing Azure Spring Clean 2023 event organised by the awesome Joe Carlyle and Thomas Thornton.
Microsoft Azure certifications have many benefits, including the potential to get your first job working with Azure, earn a promotion, keeping your skills up to date, and having greater job satisfaction.
In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover which certifications are available, learning resources, exams and renewals, money-saving tips and much more!</description></item><item><title>My Microsoft Certification Journey</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-17-my-microsoft-certification-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-17-my-microsoft-certification-journey/</guid><description>My Microsoft certifications I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to have earned all eight Microsoft Fundamentals Certifications:
Azure Fundamentals Azure Data Fundamentals Azure AI Fundamentals Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals Power Platform Fundamentals Microsoft 365 Certified: Fundamentals Dynamics 365 Fundamentals (CRM) Dynamics 365 Fundamentals (ERP) Why I study for Microsoft certifications Studying for a technical certification, Microsoft or otherwise, is a personal choice which can be motivated by several factors such as:</description></item><item><title>Asking ChatGPT about the Microsoft Power Platform</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-10-asking-chatgpt-about-power-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-10-asking-chatgpt-about-power-platform/</guid><description>I wondered what ChatGPT thinks about the Microsoft Power Platform&amp;hellip; so I asked it! The results were very interesting - here they are:
Me: What is the Microsoft Power Platform?
ChatGPT: The Microsoft Power Platform is a low-code platform that enables organizations to build custom business applications quickly and easily. It combines three products: Power Apps, Power Automate (formerly known as Microsoft Flow), and Power BI.
Power Apps is a platform for creating custom business applications for mobile devices and web browsers.</description></item><item><title>What is the Microsoft Power Apps Community?</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-03-what-is-power-apps-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-03-what-is-power-apps-community/</guid><description>The Microsoft Power Apps Community is a place where you can connect with peers, share ideas, and learn from experts for everything Power App-related.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great place to find help as well as offer help to others. In fact, when searching on Google (other search engines are available) for answers to Power App questions, I&amp;rsquo;m often directed to the Microsoft Power Apps Community where, often, someone has encountered a similar issue and helpful folks have responded with a solution.</description></item><item><title>Power Platform 2023 Release Wave 1 Plan</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</guid><description>The Microsoft Power Platform 2023 release wave 1 plan was recently announced with a TON of interesting updates!
The release plan contains hundreds of new features across Power Platform so here is a brief summary of some of my highlights:
Power BI Integrate Power BI into Teams meetings Power BI is adding new in-meeting experiences for Microsoft Teams. Users can add content like reports to Teams meetings by adding the Power BI tab to their meetings.</description></item><item><title>Festive Tech Calendar 2022</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-20-festive-tech-calendar-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-20-festive-tech-calendar-2022/</guid><description>The Festive Tech Calendar 2022 online event ran throughout December, 2022 and was fantastic!
I was privileged to be one of the co-organisers along with Gregor Suttie, Richard Hooper, Simon Lee, and Lisa Hoving. It was great to work with the organising team, speakers, our chosen charity, supporters, and everyone else, to be able to deliver a wonderful event.
There was a huge number of sessions submitted, and all event sessions are still available for catch-up here:</description></item><item><title>Azure Data Fundamentals DP-900 Courses on LinkedIn Learning</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-13-dp-900-courses-on-lil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-13-dp-900-courses-on-lil/</guid><description>One of my favourite Microsoft certifications is Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals which requires passing Exam DP-900: Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals.
LinkedIn Learning now has courses for all four of the skills measured, and I was lucky enough to be one of the instructors:
Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900) Cert Prep: 1 Core Data Concepts by Gregor Suttie
Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900) Cert Prep: 2 Working with Relational Data on Azure by Adam Wilbert</description></item><item><title>My Review of 2022</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-31-my-review-of-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-31-my-review-of-2022/</guid><description>[Photo: Sunrise over the Atlantic Ocean on my flight home to Scotland from Florida back in September.]
My 2022 My 2022 was a year of highs, lows, and lots of new experiences.
However, my highlight of the year has been the many amazing people I&amp;rsquo;ve connected with throughout my personal life, work, tech community and elsewhere. Some people I&amp;rsquo;ve known for years, others I&amp;rsquo;ve met for the first time this year.</description></item><item><title>What's all the chat about ChatGPT?</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-12-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-12-chatgpt/</guid><description>What is ChatGPT? ChatGPT is a chatbot that uses the GPT-3 language model to generate responses to user input in a conversational manner.
GPT-3 (short for &amp;ldquo;Generative Pretrained Transformer 3&amp;rdquo;) is a state-of-the-art language processing model developed by OpenAI, capable of generating human-like text.
But wait. Everything you read above was generated by ChatGPT itself!
ChatGPT&amp;rsquo;s capabilities, as listed on the intro page, are:
Remembers what user said earlier in the conversation Allows user to provide follow-up corrections Trained to decline inappropriate requests And ChatGPT&amp;rsquo;s limitations, also listed on the intro page, are:</description></item><item><title>Power Apps Ideas</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-28-power-apps-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-28-power-apps-ideas/</guid><description>Picture this: You have a Power App gallery which contains employee name text data using Power Fx formula ThisItem.Name:
Next, you want to change the text format from &amp;ldquo;Peter Gibbons&amp;rdquo; to, say, &amp;ldquo;Gibbons, Peter&amp;rdquo;.
However, you&amp;rsquo;re not (yet) a Power Fx guru. What can you do???
Well, a feature which I&amp;rsquo;ve found useful is Power Apps Ideas which allows you to transform examples to Power Fx formulas by using the power of AI models.</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-21-hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-21-hello-world/</guid><description>Hey! Welcome to my first blog post :)
I&amp;rsquo;m Keith Atherton and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a professional software developer for over 20 years. I&amp;rsquo;m Microsoft certified, a public speaker, a LinkedIn Learning instructor, and a mentor.
In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;m planning to write about all things development, including .NET, C#, SQL, Microsoft Azure, Power Platform, and non-technical subjects.
Follow me on these channels too:
LinkedIn Twitter Certifications Sessionize Power Apps Community YouTube Mastodon</description></item></channel></rss>