<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Keith Atherton</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Keith Atherton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Asking ChatGPT about the Micosoft Power Platform</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-10-asking-chatgpt-about-power-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-10-asking-chatgpt-about-power-platform/</guid><description>I wondered what ChatGPT thinks about the Micosoft Power Platform&amp;hellip; so I asked it! The results were very interesting - here they are:
Me: What is the Microsoft Power Platform?
ChatGPT: The Microsoft Power Platform is a low-code platform that enables organizations to build custom business applications quickly and easily. It combines three products: Power Apps, Power Automate (formerly known as Microsoft Flow), and Power BI.
Power Apps is a platform for creating custom business applications for mobile devices and web browsers.</description></item><item><title>What is the Microsoft Power Apps Community?</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-03-what-is-power-apps-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-02-03-what-is-power-apps-community/</guid><description>The Microsoft Power Apps Community is a place where you can connect with peers, share ideas, and learn from experts for everything Power App-related.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great place to find help as well as offer help to others. In fact, when searching on Google (other search engines are available) for answers to Power App questions, I&amp;rsquo;m often directed to the Microsoft Power Apps Community where, often, someone has encountered a similar issue and helpful folks have responded with a solution.</description></item><item><title>Power Platform 2023 Release Wave 1 Plan</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-27-power-platform-2023-release-wave-1-plan/</guid><description>The Microsoft Power Platform 2023 release wave 1 plan was recently announced with a TON of interesting updates!
The release plan contains hundreds of new features across Power Platform so here is a brief summary of some of my highlights:
Power BI Integrate Power BI into Teams meetings Power BI is adding new in-meeting experiences for Microsoft Teams. Users can add content like reports to Teams meetings by adding the Power BI tab to their meetings.</description></item><item><title>Festive Tech Calendar 2022</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-20-festive-tech-calendar-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-20-festive-tech-calendar-2022/</guid><description>The Festive Tech Calendar 2022 online event ran throughout December, 2022 and was fantastic!
I was privileged to be one of the co-organisers along with Gregor Suttie, Richard Hooper, Simon Lee, and Lisa Hoving. It was great to work with the organising team, speakers, our chosen charity, supporters, and everyone else, to be able to deliver a wonderful event.
There was a huge number of sessions submitted, and all event sessions are still available for catch-up here:</description></item><item><title>Azure Data Fundamentals DP-900 Courses on LinkedIn Learning</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-13-dp-900-courses-on-lil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2023-01-13-dp-900-courses-on-lil/</guid><description>One of my favourite Microsoft certifications is Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals which requires passing Exam DP-900: Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals.
LinkedIn Learning now has courses for all four of the skills measured, and I was lucky enough to be one of the instructors:
Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900) Cert Prep: 1 Core Data Concepts by Gregor Suttie
Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900) Cert Prep: 2 Working with Relational Data on Azure by Adam Wilbert</description></item><item><title>My Review of 2022</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-31-my-review-of-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-31-my-review-of-2022/</guid><description>[Photo: Sunrise over the Atlantic Ocean on my flight home to Scotland from Florida back in September.]
My 2022 My 2022 was a year of highs, lows, and lots of new experiences.
However, my highlight of the year has been the many amazing people I&amp;rsquo;ve connected with throughout my personal life, work, tech community and elsewhere. Some people I&amp;rsquo;ve known for years, others I&amp;rsquo;ve met for the first time this year.</description></item><item><title>What's all the chat about ChatGPT?</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-12-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-12-12-chatgpt/</guid><description>What is ChatGPT? ChatGPT is a chatbot that uses the GPT-3 language model to generate responses to user input in a conversational manner.
GPT-3 (short for &amp;ldquo;Generative Pretrained Transformer 3&amp;rdquo;) is a state-of-the-art language processing model developed by OpenAI, capable of generating human-like text.
But wait. Everything you read above was generated by ChatGPT itself!
ChatGPT&amp;rsquo;s capabilities, as listed on the intro page, are:
Remembers what user said earlier in the conversation Allows user to provide follow-up corrections Trained to decline inappropriate requests And ChatGPT&amp;rsquo;s limitations, also listed on the intro page, are:</description></item><item><title>Power Apps Ideas</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-28-power-apps-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-28-power-apps-ideas/</guid><description>Picture this: You have a Power App gallery which contains employee name text data using Power Fx formula ThisItem.Name:
Next, you want to change the text format from &amp;ldquo;Peter Gibbons&amp;rdquo; to, say, &amp;ldquo;Gibbons, Peter&amp;rdquo;.
However, you&amp;rsquo;re not (yet) a Power Fx guru. What can you do???
Well, a feature which I&amp;rsquo;ve found useful is Power Apps Ideas which allows you to transform examples to Power Fx formulas by using the power of AI models.</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-21-hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.keithatherton.com/posts/2022-11-21-hello-world/</guid><description>Hey! Welcome to my first blog post :)
I&amp;rsquo;m Keith Atherton and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a professional software developer for over 20 years. I&amp;rsquo;m Microsoft certified, a public speaker, a LinkedIn Learning instructor, and a mentor.
In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;m planning to write about all things development, including .NET, C#, SQL, Microsoft Azure, Power Platform, and non-technical subjects.
Follow me on these channels too:
LinkedIn Twitter Certifications Sessionize Power Apps Community YouTube Mastodon</description></item></channel></rss>